# **Thomas Strong**

■ strongertoms@gmail.com https://react-portfolio-tstrong.web.app 7203045826 Louisville, KY in trstrong ThomasStrong

## Summary

As a proven problem-solver my years of experience processing documents for publication, building spreadsheet calculators, and navigating software for scientific instruments (Scanning Electron Microscope, X-Ray Diffraction, SelFrag Lab, etc.), has shown me that coding is the ultimate tool of creation. I look forward to enriching my development skills while devising solutions for complex applications and architectures.

### Skills

**Languages:** JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, C#, Typescript, YAML, C++, Java

**Technologies:** Node.js, ReactJS, RESTful API, .NET, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Postman, Webpack, Maven, OpenShift, Jenkins, Angular, JFrog, DevOps

Other: Git, ArcGIS, Visual Basic, Jade 9, Minitab, NSS Spectral Imaging, Agile, Scrum

### **>** Education

Code Louisville Web Development II 2022 Web Development I 2022 Software Development I 2022

Metropolitan State University of Denver

B.S. Applied Geology (Cum Laude)

## Volunteering

Code Louisville · Jan. 2022 to Mentor Current Kentuckiana

Mentor students in a local coding boot-camp.

# **>** Employment

#### United Parcel Service - UPS

Lousiville, KY

Software Developer

Nov. 2022 to Current, Nov. 2022 to Current

- Integral to the migration of application microservices from OpenShift 3.11 to OpenShift 4
- Provide support for programming, applications, and business functions within planned durations to meet established deadlines.
- Contribute to the identification and reporting of defects in work products.
- Documentation of requirements, defect and test data, problem resolution, etc.
- Team collaboration to ensure effective communications and to support the achievement of objectives.

### The Stave Restaurant & Bar

Frankfort, KY Oct. 2018 to Mar. 2020

Server/Bartender/Supervisor

- Consistently provided outstanding customer service through creative solutions leading to retention of repeat customers.
- Experience and excellent communication facilitated the maintenance of multiple roles as necessary for continued service.

### United States Geological Survey (USGS) Physical Scientist I

Denver, Colorado Jan. 2014 to Aug. 2018

- Created and maintained an extensive database (1,000+) of sample throughput that followed the internal life of samples and required collaboration between multiple agents.
- Established pre-analysis checks of samples through X-ray diffraction and X-ray fluorescence.
- Developed and published Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for sample processing, which involved extensive testing of known and unknown methods. https://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/ofr20161022
- Constructed SOP for new equipment and provided concurrent development, as with high-voltage pulse power fragmentation (SelFrag Lab) for samples.
- Successfully captured and provided identification of samples via Scanning Electron Microscope and reflected and transmitted-light microscopes.

# > Projects

#### FindMeABeer

June 2022 to July 2022

Single Page App - https://thomasstrong.github.io/beer-finder/

- Built via React boilerplate and State Hook.
- fetch() method for API request, parse in JSON.
- Full user search form with multiple input factors.

#### Monolith Lapidary

Feb. 2022 to Mar. 2022

Product Landing Site - https://thomasstrong.github.io/Monolith\_Lapidary/

- Employed ES6 solely to generate a product landing page.
- Utilized Flexbox and Grid to create a responsive site.
- Constructed with mobile-first programming.